- Hello? - Hi - Good afternoon.
- Who is this? - Who am I speaking with? - What?
- I want to know the name of the person I’m speaking with.
- Mauricio
- Ah - You can call me Mauricio or Mauri.
- Yes. - I’ll put you through to my mother.
- Yes. - Wait, wait.
- Mommy? - Yes? - Yes? - Tell me
- Is this a public phone? I don’t know where you want to talk, ma’am.
- Yes, it’s public.
- Yes, you’re calling a public phone.
- This is a public phone.
- It’s public, but it’s my house.
- It doesn’t work anymore. - No, people don’t use it anymore.
- Honestly, I hardly see anyone using it now.
- This booth is hardly useful.
Some people call, but very few.
- No, it’s not working.
They left it for urgent service calls.
You call the PDI or the police at 1233.
- Very rarely.
- Yes, they do check them, and that,
but lately I haven’t seen anyone taking the coins out.
- They removed the booths. We keep maintaining them,
but there’s no use for booths anymore.
That is, they’re not really used.
With mobiles, they stopped being used.
- This phone at the high school?
Years ago.
It must be, I don’t know, around 30 years.
No, maybe 20 years.
- Yes, a very long time. More than 40 years.
- Yes, a long time ago, yes.
But well, this one, for many years, was
the phone there, well, in a neighborhood.
There used to be many everywhere,
but now not so much.
- There’s a public phone, but it’s broken.
- This is the only one we have. It’s a small town.
- There’s another one too.
- Only this one, the one I know here in Canelones.
- Yes, it’s the only one, of course.
- Throughout the municipality there were four public phones.
There are four or five parishes, one phone per parish.
It was like a public service.
- Yes, it’s inside like that.
- Yes, because it’s nice, a public phone
inside a clinic, that’s why it’s answered.
- And of course, since it’s a bar, people would go to the bar,
to the shop, and in the process make a call.
- No, it’s inside the office, but people can use it.
- No, on the street you can’t leave it
because people break everything.
- Yes, the phone is always where we
sometimes gather to play across the street.
- It’s the high school entrance - Inside the university.
- Yes, this line is in an educational center.
The bell just rang.
- I answered because it started ringing, but…
- Yes, because the phone was ringing…
It was strange that it rang. So I went to answer.
- You were lucky, right?
- No, no one ever called here.
- More for making calls than receiving.
- It’s very rare. - No, it doesn’t receive calls either.
- Maybe one person calls all year.
- No, because this is a coin phone
that practically doesn’t work.
People have mobile phones, and nothing, this doesn’t work.
It’s there because it was, and not to throw it away, but it doesn’t work.
- Now mobiles replaced public phones, so…
- Yes, yes. In some homes, they have four or five mobile phones.
Normally two per person.
No one complains, because, of course, with mobiles
no one complains about the phone.
Well, look, I’ll tell you something.
- What?
- Excuse me a second. Look, this is
a restaurant and we’re just serving food.
If you want to call me later, I’ll answer
without any problem, okay?
- Okay, okay
- Later, I’ll call you.
- At nine? - Whenever you want.
- Whenever you want.
You can ask for Roberto or Margarita, don’t
worry. Either of them.
- Okay.
- Thanks, bye.
Attention. CNT informs you that the number
you dialed does not exist.
Please try again later.
The number you are calling is not available at this time.
Sorry. You don’t have enough credit
to make this call.
The number you are calling
is restricted. We suggest calling later.
Dear customer, the number you dialed is
temporarily out of service.
- Hello. - Hi. - Good evening.
- Good afternoon.
It’s not a public phone, dear. I can give you a
number of a public phone in Trinidad, 4199-2598.
- Hello. - Hello. - Hello. - Hello. - Hello.
- Hello. - Hello. - Hello. - Hello.
- Hi. - Hi. - Hi, good afternoon.
- Good afternoon. - Hi - Good afternoon
- Good afternoon, speak. - Speak. - Speak.
- Tell me. - Speak. - Speak. - Yes, speak.
- Yes. - Yes. - Yes. - Yes. - Yes. - Yes. - Yes.
- But, what’s your name?
- Silvia. - Vanessa. - Rodrigo - Inés - Rosario. - Suli.
- I’m talking from Bella Unión city,
Artigas department, here on the border with Brazil.
- Are you calling from Brazil?
- Eh, in Galicia, Lugo. - In Bandera. - In Padres de Santo.
- Yumansil, Camagüey
- Eh, Chao de Pousadoiro.
- In Rivera de Piquín. - Cachilluyo.
- Eh, Jordal and Clavería. - Cuba, Trinidad.
- Jamaica. - In Guantánamo. - Pazos de Patria.
- Bienbocú. - Cuba - Cienfuegos. - Canelones. - Uruguay
- You’ve never been to Trinidad?
- No.
- You have to come to Trinidad
- Yes, exactly.
- Of course!
Come visit the free shops they have.
- I’d love to meet you.
- You can come here to Bella Unión.
- Yes. - To meet.
- We’re close to the museums.
Close to the steps.
Close to the church.
- All of them. - There’s a lot to see here.
- Yes, quite a lot.
- So, do you think we could meet one day?
- Yes, of course. - Really? - Yes.
- And when will you come? When will you come to Cuba?
I’d be very pleased to meet you. - Come, yes.
- And I’ll offer my home. Ask for the public phone of Tres Cruces and they’ll tell you immediately.
- Ah, good. I hope you come.
I hope to see you to show you many things.
- Come, yes. - Ah, good. Call again, it’s a pleasure.
- And truly, it was a pleasure because no…
- The things of life, I had just stepped out of the room here
and picked up the phone.
- I really enjoyed talking to you.
- Truly.
- Keep calling.
- Likewise.
- Okay, dear. - Okay - Okay, okay.
- Okay. - Okay, take care.
- Thank you. - You’re welcome, my dear. - Thanks.
- Please. - Thanks. - You’re welcome. - Thanks.
- Take care. - Yes, yes.
- Thanks. - Come on. - You’re welcome.
- Bye. - Bye. - Okay, bye. - Bye.
- A kiss, good luck. - Bye, bye.