...
-Hello?
-Hi
-Good afternoon
-Who is this?
Who am I
speakng with?
-What?
-I want to know the
name of the person
I’m speakng with
-Mauricio
-Ah
You can call me
Mauricio or Mauri
-Yes
-I’ll put you
through to my mother
-Yes
Eh
Wait, wait
-Mommy?
-Yes
-Tell me
-Is this a public
phone? I don’t know
where you want to
talk, ma’am.
-Yes it’s public
-Yes you’re calling
a public phone
This is a
public phone
It’s public,
but it’s my house
It doesn’t
work anymore
No, people don’t
use it anymore
Honestly, I hardly
see anyone using
it now
This booth is
hardly useful. Some
people call, but
very few
No it’s not working
They left it for
urgent service calls
You call the PDI or
the police at 1233
-Very rarely
-Yes they do check
them, but lately I
haven’t seen anyone
taking the coins out
-They removed the
booths. We keep
maintaining them,
but there’s no use
for booths anymore
That is, they’re not
really used.
With mobiles, they
stopped being used
-This phone at the
high school?
Years ago
It must be,
I don’t know,
around 30 years,
maybe 20 years
Yes a very long
time. More than
40 years
-Yes a long time ago
-But well, this one,
for many years, was
the phone, well, in
let's say,
a neighborhood
There used to be
many everywhere,
but now,
not so much
There’s a public
phone, but it’s
broken
This is the only
one we have
It’s a small town
There’s another one
-Only this one, the
one I know here in
Canelones
-Yes it’s the only
one, of course
-Throughout the
municipality there
were 4 public phones
There are 4 or 5
parishes, 1 phone
per parish
It was like a public
service
-Yes it’s inside
-Yes because it’s
nice, a public phone
inside a clinic,thats
why it’s answered
And of course since
it’s a bar, people
would go to the bar,
to the shop,
and, in the process,
make a call
-No, it’s inside the
office, but people
can use it.
-No, on the street
you can’t leave it
because people
break everything
-Yes this phone is
where we sometimes
gather to play across
the street
-It’s the
high school entrance
-Inside the
university
-Yes this line is
in an educational
center
The bell just rang.
I answered because
it started ringing,
but…
-Yes because the
phone was ringing
It was strange
that it rang.
So I came to answer
It was luck,
right?
-No, no one ever
called here
-More for making
calls than receiving
-It’s very rare
-No, it doesn’t
receive calls either
Maybe one person
calls all year.
-No, because this
is a coin phone
that practically
doesn’t work
People have mobile
phones, and this
doesn’t work. It’s
there because it was
and not to throw it
away, but it
doesn’t work
-Now mobiles
replaced public
phones, so
Yes yes
In some homes
they have 4 or 5
mobile phones
Normally two
per person
-No one complains,
because, of course,
with mobiles no one
need the phone
Well, look, I’ll
tell you something
-What?
-Excuse me,
just a second
Look, this is
a restaurant
and we’re just
serving food.
If you want to
call me later,
I’ll answer without
any problem, okay?
-Okay, okay
-Later I’ll call you
-At 9h?
-Whenever you want
-You can ask for
Roberto or Margarita
don’t worry
Either of them
-Okay.
-Thanks, bye
-Attention: CNT
informs you that
-the number you
dialed doesn't exist
-Please try
again later
-The number you are
calling is not available
at this time
-Sorry, you don’t have
enough credit to
make this call
-The number you are
calling is restricted
-We suggest
calling later
-Dear customer, the
number you dialed
-is temporarily out
of service
-Hello
-Hi
-Good evening
-Good afternoon
-It’s not a public
phone, dear
I can give you a
number
of a public phone in
Trinidad: 4199-2598
-Hello
-Hi
-Hi good afternoon
-Good afternoon
-Hi
-Good afternoon,
speak
-Speak
-Tell me
-Yes speak
-Yes
Yes
-But, what’s your
name?
-Silvia
-Vanessa
-Rodrigo
-Inés
-Rosario
-Suli
-I’m talking from
Bella Unión city,
Artigas department,
here on the border
with Brazil
-Are you calling
from Brazil?
-Eh, in Galicia,
Lugo.
-Banderas
-In Padres de Santo
-Yumansil,
-Camagüey
-Chao de Pousadoiro
-In Rivera de Piquin
-Cachilluyo
-Eh, Jordal
and Clavería
-Cuba, Trinidad
-Jamaica
-In Guantánamo
-Pazos de Patria
-Bienbocú
-Cuba
-Cienfuegos
-Canelones
-Uruguay
-You’ve never been
to Trinidad?
-No
-You have to
come to Trinidad
Yes exactly
-Of course!
Come visit the free
shops they have
-I’d love to
meet you
-You can come here
to Bella Unión
-Yes
-To meet
-We’re close to the
museums. Close
to the steps
Close to the church
-All of them
-There’s a lot
to see here
-Yes quite a lot
-So, do you think we
could meet one day?
-Yes of course
-Really?
-Yes
-And when will you
come? When will you
come to Cuba?
-I’d be very pleased
to meet you
-Come, yes
-And I’ll offer my
home. Ask for the
public phone of
Tres Cruces
and they’ll tell
you immediately
-Ah,
good. I hope
- you come. I hope
to see you to show
you many things
-Come, yes
-Ah, good
-Call again, it’s
a pleasure
-And truly,
it was a pleasure
-The things of life
I had just stepped
out here and picked
up the phone
-I really enjoyed
talking to you
-Truly
-Keep calling
-Likewise
-Okay, dear
-Okay
-Okay, okay
-Okay, take care
-Thank you
-You’re welcome,
my dear
-Thanks
-Please
-You’re welcome
-Thanks
-Take care
-Yes yes
-Thanks
-Come on
-You’re welcome
-Bye
-Bye.
-Okay, bye
-Bye
-A kiss
-Good luck
-Bye, bye