Hello.
Hi.
Good afternoon.
Who is this?
Juan.
Is that your name?
Yes.
Who is speaking?
Mauricio.
Can you call me…
Can you call me Mauricio?
Mauri.
From where?
This phone too.
We have a store here.
I want to speak with whoever you want to see.
Should I put you through to my mother?
Yes.
Okay.
Hey, wait, wait.
Mom.
Yes, tell me.
This is a public phone.
I don’t know where you want to talk, ma’am.
It is public.
You called a public phone.
This is a public phone.
It’s public.
But it’s my house.
No.
Look, this is a coin-operated phone that practically doesn’t work.
People have mobile phones now, so nothing.
This.
No, no, it doesn’t work.
This one.
This one, because it was there.
And they didn’t throw it away.
But it doesn’t work.
Because it’s public.
Right?
In front of the Cocinería, there is a public phone.
But it’s broken.
Doesn’t work.
Yes, it’s in the system, but…
I don’t see anyone using it.
Honestly, I hardly see people using it.
Very little, very little use for this booth.
Some people call, but very few.
Uh.
No, no, they don’t use it anymore.
It’s useless now.
Very few.
Eh?
From this phone, you can call local landlines.
Yes, from…
Yes, they can check them and all that.
But I haven’t seen anyone recently collecting coins.
No, it’s not working.
It’s…
It is.
Left for urgent service calls, like in case of an accident or a robbery.
You call the police or Carabineros at 1233.
Eh!
They removed the booths.
We still maintain them, but no one uses booths anymore.
Meaning no one uses it; with mobiles it stopped being used.
This phone has been in the school for years.
Must be like 30 years, or 20 maybe.
Yes, it has.
A very long time.
More than 40 years?
Yes, a long time.
But well, yes.
For many years, it was the main phone.
In a small town of about 100 inhabitants.
There used to be many places, but not anymore.
This is the only one we have, it’s a small town.
There’s another one.
Only this one I know in Canelones.
Here in Bella Unión, another, maybe 112 in total because the others were removed.
Yes, it’s the only one left.
Within the municipality, there were…
Four public phones.
Eh.
According to the…
Mmm.
How do you say?
Parishes.
According to the parishes, each parish had one.
A public phone.
And here in the Rivera de Viking municipality, there were four or five parishes, one phone in each parish.
And since it’s a bar, people would go to the bar or store and make a call.
Uh-huh.
Mhm.
It was like a public service.
Yes, it was useful.
A public phone inside a sanatorium.
That’s why it’s answered.
This phone is sometimes used by people playing in front.
In front.
Meaning inside this place we are talking from.
The phone is inside the room.
The phone cannot be removed because people need it.
They would break everything.
Nothing more to say.
No, don’t come in here.
In Bella Unión, there’s none.
There’s one upstairs.
Not inside the office, but people can use it.
And we are close to the…
And the entrance to the school.
Inside the university?
Yes, this line is in an educational center.
Aqui está a tradução do seu SRT para inglês, mantendo o mesmo formato pronto para uso:
The bell just rang.
I answered it because it started ringing, but…
Because the phone rang.
I mean, it was strange that it rang, so I went to answer it.
And I went by luck, and indeed.
Haven’t they ever called here?
Sometimes, not.
No, not much.
Now that I’m in the room, I saw them ringing, so I answered.
But no, no, we haven’t said anything.
Do the kids use it more to call than to…?
To receive calls.
It’s very rare.
No, it doesn’t receive calls either.
Maybe they call one person all year.
No one complains.
Because, of course, with mobiles, nobody complains about the phone.
Now, cell phones replaced public phones.
So it doesn’t…
No, it hasn’t…
Mobiles.
Cell phones?
Yes, yes, yes, many.
Some homes even have four or five cell phones.
Normally, they have two mobile devices per person.
Ah, I didn’t know that.
Yes, I didn’t know.
Later, it became coin-operated and…
And now it’s no longer used.
You can call with a card or with money, both options.
If you deposit money, you can talk.
Do they have a booth?
They have a booth where they can have privacy.
Well, look, I’ll tell you something.
Excuse me for a second.
Look, this is a restaurant and we are right in the middle of meals.
If you want, you can call me later.
Yes, I’ll answer you with no problem.
Okay.
Alright.
Thanks.
You can ask for Roberto.
Or Margarita?
Don’t worry.
Either one.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
You too.
See you.
Bye.
Attention.
The number you have dialed is temporarily out of service.
We’re sorry, the number you dialed does not exist.
Please check it.
Thank you.
The phone you are calling is not available at this time.
Please try again later.
CNT informs you that the number you dialed does not exist.
Please consult the CNT Information Service.
We’re sorry, the number you are calling is unavailable at this moment.
Access to the number you dialed is restricted.
The dialed number is not available.
We suggest calling later.
The number you are calling is busy.
Dear customer, the number you dialed is out of service.
Thank you.
Hello.
The call dropped today.
Can you repeat that?
Of course.
What?
What do you mean the call dropped?
You’ll have to call.
This is a public phone.
It’s, uh…
Ah.
You have to call another time.
Another?
Well, another time.
Alright.
Okay.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Uh.
No.
Bye.
Alright.
Hello?
Hi.
Good afternoon.
Well.
It’s not a public one.
My dear.
Eh?
Can I give you a public number in Trinidad?
41 99 2 98
Hello?
Hi?
Hi.
Hello?
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Yes, speaking.
Yes?
Tell me, tell me, tell me, speak.
Speak.
Yes, speak.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
But…
What’s your name?
Silvia.
My name is Vanessa Rodríguez.
Inés Rosario.
But don’t call me Zuli.
I’m talking from the city of Bella Unión, Artigas Department, here, on the border with Brazil.
Calling from Brazil.
Eh?
In Galicia.
Lugo.
Flag.
The father from Santo José in Camagüey is not there.
From Pousadoiro in Ribera de Piquín.
So I can give you Cuba.
Trinidad.
Jamaica in Guantánamo.
Paso de Patria.
Ñeembucú, Cuba, Cienfuegos.
Canelones, Uruguay.
Also from here in Uruguay with Brazil and Argentina.
You’ve never been to Trinidad.
But no.
You have to come to Trinidad.
You must have Trinidad.
Yes, exactly.
Of course I’ll visit, I have several [people/places].
Me.
I’d love to meet you.
You can come by here to see.
Yes.
There.
To see.
To visit?
No, here.
Here in Bella Unión we have five “frijoles.”
So we are close to the museums, close to the stairs, close to the church.
All.
Yes, close to the church?
Yes.
There’s a lot to see here.
Yes, quite a lot.
Are there many restaurants?
All of them?
No.
So do you think one day we’ll be able to meet?
Yes, of course.
Yes, yes.
And when will you come?
When will you come to Cuba?
Actually, soon.
To see my life.
Hahaha.
So I’d very kindly like to meet you and offer you my home.
Eh?
So.
Yes.
I live here.
Here in Trinidad, near the Calvary of the Three Crosses.
If you ask for the public phone of Las Tres Cruces, they’ll immediately tell you yes.
Ah, okay, I hope you come.
I hope to see you to show you many things.
Exactly.
Here is my…
My house.
Yes, yes, yes.
Come.
Yes.
Ah, okay, I’ll call, it’s very pleasant for me.
And truly, it was a pleasure because you made my day; I had gone to the living room here and answered the phone.
I really enjoyed talking to you; I really enjoyed talking to you.
Ah, right?
Same here.
Keep calling.
Later I’ll call you at nine, whenever you want, at whatever time you want.
If I can connect, I have to study.
Go my…
Life.
Well, well.
Well.
Okay, okay.
Thanks.
You’re welcome.
My heart.
Well, take care.
Thanks.
Alright.
Well, come.
Thanks.
You’re welcome.
Well, nothing.
See you later.
Thanks.
Go ahead.
Nothing.
Take care.
Well, well.
Okay.
Yes.
Thanks.
A kiss.
Good luck.
See you later.
Bye.
Goodbye.
See you later.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Bye.